<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Forensics on BMHS TSA</title><link>https://bmhstsa.com/tags/forensics/</link><description>Recent content in Forensics on BMHS TSA</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:58:15 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bmhstsa.com/tags/forensics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wireshark 2</title><link>https://bmhstsa.com/post/wireshark-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:58:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhstsa.com/post/wireshark-2/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 7/10 Skill: 5/10 Time: 3 hours Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
This is another Wireshark challenge, expanding on the first challenge. Wireshark is a piece of software used to monitor network traffic.
Initial analysis Starting off I (loogalicious) opened the file in Wireshark. After browsing through it, I noticed 90 or so flags in the responses from http://18.217.1.57/flag and the AWS EC2 token in packet 4344 caught my eye: After Wakeful-Cloud and I made a script to extract all of the flags, I realized they were red herrings.</description></item><item><title>Wireshark Doo Dooo Do Doo</title><link>https://bmhstsa.com/post/wireshark-doo-dooo-do-doo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:48:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhstsa.com/post/wireshark-doo-dooo-do-doo/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 7/10 Skill: 4/10 Time: 15-30 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
This challenge is a Wireshark-based challenge, which involves analyzing network traffic through Wireshark.
What software do you need? Wireshark and a ROT13 decoder, which you can find online.
What do you need to know in order to solve it? You need to know how to export Wireshark objects into HTTP and possibly how to recognize ROT13 encryptions if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend 20 minutes looking up different decryption websites.</description></item><item><title>Static Aint Always Noise</title><link>https://bmhstsa.com/post/static-aint-always-noise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:57:30 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhstsa.com/post/static-aint-always-noise/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 8/10 Skill: 2/10 Time: 3 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
What software do you need? Notepad or a text editor.
What do you need to know in order to solve it? That nobody expects Notepad.
What do you actually do? Open the file in Notepad and CTRL+F for picoCTF.</description></item><item><title>Matryoshka Doll</title><link>https://bmhstsa.com/post/matryoshka-doll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:32:39 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhstsa.com/post/matryoshka-doll/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 6/10 Skill: 4/10 Time: 10 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
What software do you need? Any type of zip extraction, 7zip or WinRAR work fine.
What do you need to know in order to solve it? The aspect of this challenge is to find hidden files inside image files.
What do you actually do? Archive the original file with (in my case) WinRAR, then extract it.</description></item></channel></rss>