<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>picoCTF 2021 on BMHS TSA</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/categories/picoctf-2021/</link><description>Recent content in picoCTF 2021 on BMHS TSA</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 16:06:11 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/categories/picoctf-2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>crackme-py</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/crackme-py/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 16:06:11 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/crackme-py/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 5/10 Skill: 3/10 Time: 5-10 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
The CTF starts out by giving you a python file called crackme.py. When you run it, it just takes two numbers as input and outputs the largest. Not very helpful for finding flags, unless&amp;hellip;
How do we find the flag? When you open the file in any text editor, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that there&amp;rsquo;s more to this program than it seems.</description></item><item><title>Wireshark 2</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/wireshark-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:58:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/wireshark-2/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 7/10 Skill: 5/10 Time: 3 hours Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
This is another Wireshark challenge, expanding on the first challenge. Wireshark is a piece of software used to monitor network traffic.
Initial analysis Starting off I (loogalicious) opened the file in Wireshark. After browsing through it, I noticed 90 or so flags in the responses from http://18.217.1.57/flag and the AWS EC2 token in packet 4344 caught my eye: After Wakeful-Cloud and I made a script to extract all of the flags, I realized they were red herrings.</description></item><item><title>Wireshark Doo Dooo Do Doo</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/wireshark-doo-dooo-do-doo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:48:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/wireshark-doo-dooo-do-doo/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 7/10 Skill: 4/10 Time: 15-30 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
This challenge is a Wireshark-based challenge, which involves analyzing network traffic through Wireshark.
What software do you need? Wireshark and a ROT13 decoder, which you can find online.
What do you need to know in order to solve it? You need to know how to export Wireshark objects into HTTP and possibly how to recognize ROT13 encryptions if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend 20 minutes looking up different decryption websites.</description></item><item><title>X Marks the Spot</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/x-marks-the-spot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 23:39:19 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/x-marks-the-spot/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 3/10 Skill: 7/10 Time: 4-6 hours Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
Preface This write-up assumes you understand what an injection vulnerability is. If you don&amp;rsquo;t you, should check out Web Gauntlet 2.
What is XPath? XPath is the standard way of querying data from an XML document (Similar to SQL). There are a few basic things you need to know about XPath:</description></item><item><title>Mod 13</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/mod-13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:58:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/mod-13/</guid><description>Mod 26 This is a rot 13 cypher!
What is ROT 13? ROT 13 is a cipher where every letter is rotated by 13 letters within the alphabet. It is a type of caesar cipher.
How can this be reversed? Rot 13 can be reversed the same way as it is encypted, by rotating the letters by thirteen charecters. In Python we can simply take the ASCII value of each letter (take out special charecters and numbers),and add thirteen, before using the modulo operator to loop backto the beginning of the alphabet.</description></item><item><title>Static Aint Always Noise</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/static-aint-always-noise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:57:30 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/static-aint-always-noise/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 8/10 Skill: 2/10 Time: 3 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
What software do you need? Notepad or a text editor.
What do you need to know in order to solve it? That nobody expects Notepad.
What do you actually do? Open the file in Notepad and CTRL+F for picoCTF.</description></item><item><title>Magikarp Ground Mission</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/magikarp-ground-mission/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:46:31 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/magikarp-ground-mission/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 4/10 Skill: 3/10 Time: 5-10 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
What is SSH? SSH (Secure SHell) is a protocol for securely transmitting commands to a remote computer. It makes it possible to access files, run commands, and more, just from inside the terminal. More information can be found here.
Doing the challenge Pico already gives you the command to use. When you first log in, the directory you&amp;rsquo;re in has 1of3.</description></item><item><title>Matryoshka Doll</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/matryoshka-doll/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 16:32:39 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/matryoshka-doll/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 6/10 Skill: 4/10 Time: 10 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
What software do you need? Any type of zip extraction, 7zip or WinRAR work fine.
What do you need to know in order to solve it? The aspect of this challenge is to find hidden files inside image files.
What do you actually do? Archive the original file with (in my case) WinRAR, then extract it.</description></item><item><title>Web Gauntlet 3</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/web-gauntlet-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:32:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/web-gauntlet-3/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 3/10 Skill: 6/10 Time: 30 minutes (Assuming you already solved Web Gauntlet 2) Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
Preface This is the followup challenge to Web Gauntlet 2 which itself is a followup to Web Gauntlet. This article assumes you&amp;rsquo;ve already solved Web Gauntlet 2.
What&amp;rsquo;s different? Not a whole lot - just the maximum user input length. Our previous exploit (admi'||CHAR(1540/LENGTH( and ))||') is 29 characters long.</description></item><item><title>Web Gauntlet 2</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/web-gauntlet-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:26:46 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/web-gauntlet-2/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 3/10 Skill: 6/10 Time: 2-3 hours Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
Preface This is the followup challenge to Web Gauntlet.
What are SQL injections? SQL injections occur when a server improperly handles user input in such a way that the user can write SQL queries and run them on the server. For example, lets say we&amp;rsquo;re running a simple web server that performs a username/password lookup:</description></item><item><title>Get Ahead</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/get-ahead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 22:38:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/get-ahead/</guid><description>Challenge Rating Artificialness: 5/10 Skill: 3/10 Time: 5 minutes Learn more about how we rate challenges here.
What are HTTP verbs? Normally when you access a website, your browser makes an HTTP request to GET content from the server. However, your browser isn&amp;rsquo;t always fetching data from a server, sometimes it POSTs data too (Such as when logging in to a website). HTTP verbs are the standardized method for telling the server what to do.</description></item><item><title>Rating</title><link>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/rating/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 22:31:14 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://bmhs-tsa.github.io/post/rating/</guid><description>We rank CTF challenges on the following metrics:
Artificialness Skill Time Artificialness This metric measures how contrived or artificial a challenge is. This metric is measured on a scale from 1 to 10 where 1 represents a very realistic challenge while a 10 represents a very artificial challenge.
Skill This metric measures how much skill a challenge requires to solve. If multiple ways of solving a challenge are available, this metrics should reflect the easiest one.</description></item></channel></rss>